<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Timeline on Micaelle Nogueira</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/</link><description>Recent content in Timeline on Micaelle Nogueira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Admitted to the Technical University of Munich</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/second_degree_tum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/second_degree_tum/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-dream-come-true">A dream come true&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Studying abroad has been a dream for over a decade! When I finally had the opportunity to live overseas, I set that as my main goal. While still in Brazil, I found TUM&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>, the Technical University of Munich, as the place where I wanted to study and build my academic life abroad. Getting admitted after an extensive application process was literally a dream come true!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the way, this website is an outcome of my application for enrollment in the Bachelor in Management &amp;amp; Technology&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup> program, as a portfolio and a creative way to show an extension of my technical skills related to Computer Engineering, the field of specialization in technology that I chose in this program.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="a-dream-come-true">A dream come true</h2>
<p>Studying abroad has been a dream for over a decade! When I finally had the opportunity to live overseas, I set that as my main goal. While still in Brazil, I found TUM<sup>1</sup>, the Technical University of Munich, as the place where I wanted to study and build my academic life abroad. Getting admitted after an extensive application process was literally a dream come true!</p>
<p>By the way, this website is an outcome of my application for enrollment in the Bachelor in Management &amp; Technology<sup>2</sup> program, as a portfolio and a creative way to show an extension of my technical skills related to Computer Engineering, the field of specialization in technology that I chose in this program.</p>
<h2 id="the-perfect-fit">The perfect fit</h2>
<p>I have found the Bachelor in Management &amp; Technology program to be the perfect fit for my career and my ambition to study at TUM.</p>
<p>For about 6 years, I have developed and honed my management skills. On the other hand, I have never properly studied technology, although I have some skills. I can say that programming is a latent aptitude. When I was between 13 and 14 years old, I really wanted to study Computer Engineering. Throughout my career, I worked alongside the IT team several times, and the most I did was design mock-ups of tools and features. I have always been close enough to learning to code. In fact, I always wanted to know how to code to be independent, build my own tools and features, and meet my needs more quickly and autonomously.</p>
<p>Combining management and technology in a bachelor’s degree is combining the best of me! That is exactly the balance I have been looking for.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.tum.de/en/">TUM</a> is a public university in Munich. It is one of the largest universities in Germany. A University of Excellence under the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_Universities_Excellence_Initiative">German Universities Excellence Initiative</a>, TUM is considered the top university in Germany according to major rankings of 2022 and is among the leading universities in the European Union.</small><br/>
<small><sup>2</sup> <a href="https://www.mgt.tum.de/programs/bachelor-management-technology/munich">Bachelor in Management &amp; Technology</a> is a program of <a href="https://www.mgt.tum.de/">TUM School of Management</a> that combines management courses (70%) with a specialization in technology focusing on Digital Technologies (30%).</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Started taking private German lessons</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_german2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_german2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="new-year-new-beginnings">New year, new beginnings&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I love that feeling of starting something new at the beginning of the year, even if it means restarting something!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In January 2020, I started a German course at a language school&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup> and completed the A1 module in about 2 months of intensive classes. However, it had to be stopped due to COVID-19 restrictions. In mid-May, I resumed the learning process using an online platform from an excellent German school&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>. After a few months, I realized that it was not really working. I was progressing very well, passing the exercises without any problem, but I did not feel that the knowledge was taking root. I gave it some time, but that feeling remained. So I contacted a German teacher and arranged the beginning of private lessons in January 2021.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="new-year-new-beginnings">New year, new beginnings</h2>
<p>I love that feeling of starting something new at the beginning of the year, even if it means restarting something!</p>
<p>In January 2020, I started a German course at a language school<sup>1</sup> and completed the A1 module in about 2 months of intensive classes. However, it had to be stopped due to COVID-19 restrictions. In mid-May, I resumed the learning process using an online platform from an excellent German school<sup>2</sup>. After a  few months, I realized that it was not really working. I was progressing very well, passing the exercises without any problem, but I did not feel that the knowledge was taking root. I gave it some time, but that feeling remained. So I contacted a German teacher and arranged the beginning of private lessons in January 2021.</p>
<p>The lessons ran effectively until the end of September, when I reached the B1 level and started a bachelor’s degree at the Technical University of Munich. While at University, I kept up my German language learning during my first term.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.edeltraud-muc.de/en/">Edeltraud</a> is a German school located in Munich.</small><br/>
<small><sup>2</sup> <a href="https://www.goethe.de/en/index.html">Goethe-Institut</a> is the cultural institute of the Federal Republic of Germany that operates worldwide. It promotes the study of the German language abroad and encourages international cultural exchange and relations.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Learned my first Programming Language</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/learning_python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/learning_python/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-unsuccessful-attempt">The unsuccessful attempt&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In mid-2015, I was very committed to learning a certain programming language, R&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>, due to my interest in furthering the studies in the statistics that I was studying on my MBA in finance. I decided to study alone, on weekends, the only free time I had. I had started an online course, but soon I realized that I should know the basics of programming first. I was stuck at the beginning of this course and gave up. Nonetheless, the idea of acquiring skills in such a tool that could improve data manipulation and analysis never left my mind.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-unsuccessful-attempt">The unsuccessful attempt</h2>
<p>In mid-2015, I was very committed to learning a certain programming language, R<sup>1</sup>, due to my interest in furthering the studies in the statistics that I was studying on my MBA in finance. I decided to study alone, on weekends, the only free time I had. I had started an online course, but soon I realized that I should know the basics of programming first. I was stuck at the beginning of this course and gave up. Nonetheless, the idea of acquiring skills in such a tool that could improve data manipulation and analysis never left my mind.</p>
<h2 id="the-successful-attempt">The successful attempt</h2>
<p>As an alternative to the quarantine times due to COVID-19 – when I realized that all my plans were frozen – I decided to make this happen: learn a programming language. This time, I chose to learn Python<sup>2</sup> which has an easy-to-understand syntax. In addition to the potential to be a tool in my work of analyzing financial data, forecasting, and creating growth strategies, learning Python also serves a general purpose that would broaden my field of knowledge.</p>
<p>I completed an online course at the University of Michigan and since then have been studying on my own, relying on different resources, such as books and the Python documentation, solving coding challenges, and being mentored by my husband, who is a Pythonista with over 20 years of experience.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.r-project.org/">R</a> is a programming language and free software environment for statistical computing and graphics. In other words, R is an integrated suite of software facilities for data manipulation, calculation and graphical display.</small><br/>
<small><sup>2</sup> <a href="https://www.python.org/">Python</a> is a multipurpose programming language that emphasizes code readability. Its language constructs and object-oriented approach aim to help programmers write clear, logical code for small and large-scale projects.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Volunteered for a 36-hour hackathon</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/volunteer_hackillinois/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/volunteer_hackillinois/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="hackillinois">HackIllinois&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Every year, since 2014, on the last weekend of February, there is a 36-hour university hackathon run by students, the HackIllinois&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>. It is the largest open-source hackathon in the world and brings in approximately 1,000 students from across the United States. An event like this requires a lot of teamwork. In the 2020 edition, I joined the team of volunteers, willing to help out the staff at any level.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="hackillinois">HackIllinois</h2>
<p>Every year, since 2014, on the last weekend of February, there is a 36-hour university hackathon run by students, the HackIllinois<sup>1</sup>. It is the largest open-source hackathon in the world and brings in approximately 1,000 students from across the United States. An event like this requires a lot of teamwork. In the 2020 edition, I joined the team of volunteers, willing to help out the staff at any level.</p>
<h2 id="the-opportunity">The opportunity</h2>
<p>This opportunity came across because my husband is one of the mentors. He has been mentoring HackIllinois for four consecutive years. For his third time, we travelled together and contributed in different ways to this amazing event.</p>
<br/>
<script type="text/javascript" src="/js/lightbox.js"></script>
<link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/lightbox.css">

<style>
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery li {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%;}
    .image-gallery li a {text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important; color: #777;}
    .image-gallery li a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery li a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
</style>


<ul class="image-gallery">
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/hackillinois/hackillinois_hu_3d5fe24f0f10ca8b.JPG" title="hackillinois" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/hackillinois/hackillinois_hu_b211155bd47c7294.JPG" alt="hackillinois" title="hackillinois">
    </a>
  </li>  

</ul>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://2020.hackillinois.org/">HackIllinois</a> is an open-source hackathon that takes place at the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, USA. </small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Started a German course</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_german/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_german/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="new-year-new-projects">New year, new projects&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I love that feeling of starting something new at the beginning of the year. I was very excited to start learning German at a language school&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup> at last. On January 7th, I was completely lost on my first day of school. That first week was challenging. In the next two months, I realized that I was already quite acquainted with the language and enjoying learning it.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="new-year-new-projects">New year, new projects</h2>
<p>I love that feeling of starting something new at the beginning of the year. I was very excited to start learning German at a language school<sup>1</sup> at last. On January 7th, I was completely lost on my first day of school. That first week was challenging. In the next two months, I realized that I was already quite acquainted with the language and enjoying learning it.</p>
<h2 id="oops-its-2020">Oops, it&rsquo;s 2020</h2>
<p>Unfortunately, these pandemic times kept me away from classes. I considered going back to school many times, but it was not the safest method at the time, although it is the most efficient in my point of view.</p>
<p>The alternative was to start an online German course at Goethe<sup>2</sup>.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.edeltraud-muc.de/en/">Edeltraud</a> is a German school located in Munich.</small><br/>
<small><sup>2</sup> <a href="https://www.goethe.de/en/index.html">Goethe-Institut</a> is the cultural institute of the Federal Republic of Germany that operates worldwide. It promotes the study of the German language abroad and encourages international cultural exchange and relations.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Travelled abroad to study English</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_london/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_london/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="confidence-is-the-key">Confidence is the key&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I completed the English course in Brazil a month before moving to Europe. I believed that I was ready to travel abroad and communicate fluently. However, it was a shock when I moved and realized that I could barely understand what people were saying. The different accents sounded like another language to me. It took me about 2 months to train my ears and get used to it. I tried to learn German and improve my English at the same time, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t work. At least, it worked to show me that I needed to focus on one language at a time. So I chose to focus on improving my English, finishing what I had already started.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="confidence-is-the-key">Confidence is the key</h2>
<p>I completed the English course in Brazil a month before moving to Europe. I believed that I was ready to travel abroad and communicate fluently. However, it was a shock when I moved and realized that I could barely understand what people were saying. The different accents sounded like another language to me. It took me about 2 months to train my ears and get used to it. I tried to learn German and improve my English at the same time, but it didn&rsquo;t work. At least, it worked to show me that I needed to focus on one language at a time. So I chose to focus on improving my English, finishing what I had already started.</p>
<p>I participated in language exchange meetups, started to study individually at home, and met a person who agreed to do a tandem. These efforts have really improved my English skills, except for one and fundamental thing: confidence. When I realized that I was afraid to open my mouth and make mistakes all the time, I decided to take the next step: go to a country that has English as its mother tongue.</p>
<h2 id="full-immersion">Full immersion</h2>
<p>I went to London to study at an English School<sup>1</sup>. I took a preparation course to obtain the international certification, IELTS (International English Language Testing System) and took extra special classes &ldquo;Speaking with Confidence&rdquo;. It was an intensive course of 22.5 hours per week for 2 months (8 weeks). In addition, I chose to live with a family in the first month and with a different family in the second month, in order to expand my experience and have a complete immersion.</p>
<p>Going to London was a milestone in my learning process. I improved in two months what I couldn&rsquo;t do before. More than advancing to level C1 on the school exit test and achieving the minimum IELTS required for a master&rsquo;s degree in Europe, I gained the confidence I was looking for and returned to Munich ready to learn the next language: German.</p>
<br/>
<script type="text/javascript" src="/js/lightbox.js"></script>
<link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/lightbox.css">

<style>
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery li {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%;}
    .image-gallery li a {text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important; color: #777;}
    .image-gallery li a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery li a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
</style>


<ul class="image-gallery">
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/london/Certificate_hu_4fad0557a281b90c.jpg" title="Certificate" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/london/Certificate_hu_a1bef6e3e44ab16d.jpg" alt="Certificate" title="Certificate">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/london/Class_hu_35f5c3a190ff33b6.jpg" title="Class" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/london/Class_hu_51c54973c6760d1e.jpg" alt="Class" title="Class">
    </a>
  </li>  

</ul>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="http://www.ecenglish.com/">EC English</a> is a language centre with 25 schools around the world that offers academic, business and general English courses.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Started to mentor startups and small businesses</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/mentoring_online/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/mentoring_online/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-passion-for-mentoring-awakens">The passion for mentoring awakens&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In mid-2019, I was approached by a person living in Brazil, asking for guidance in the development of their startup, which was at a very early stage. As I was about to travel to Brazil on vacation in a few weeks, I arranged to meet them in person and learn more about their project. We had some meetings during my stay in Brazil, I met their partners and started to mentor them. I returned to Munich and continued this mentorship for a few months.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="the-passion-for-mentoring-awakens">The passion for mentoring awakens</h3>
<p>In mid-2019, I was approached by a person living in Brazil, asking for guidance in the development of their startup, which was at a very early stage. As I was about to travel to Brazil on vacation in a few weeks, I arranged to meet them in person and learn more about their project. We had some meetings during my stay in Brazil, I met their partners and started to mentor them. I returned to Munich and continued this mentorship for a few months.</p>
<p>In the meantime, other people have reached me, which made me decide to be an empowering agent of entrepreneurship, voluntarily and remotely guiding startups and small businesses in Brazil, fostering their strategies in different areas, from business plans to marketing.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Moved to another continent</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/moved_munich/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/moved_munich/</guid><description>&lt;p>Going abroad was always a dream: living a completely different lifestyle, exploring new experiences, getting used to other cultures and customs, learning a foreign language&amp;hellip; In mid-2016, I decided to include it on my wish list and add a purpose: studying abroad, which since my graduation had been a dream. I set as a goal a master&amp;rsquo;s degree related to economics and consumer behaviour. I also designated a starting point, starting in 2018, after my wedding.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Going abroad was always a dream: living a completely different lifestyle, exploring new experiences, getting used to other cultures and customs, learning a foreign language&hellip; In mid-2016, I decided to include it on my wish list and add a purpose: studying abroad, which since my graduation had been a dream. I set as a goal a master&rsquo;s degree related to economics and consumer behaviour. I also designated a starting point, starting in 2018, after my wedding.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, life flows freely and we have no total control over it. At the end of 2017, a great opportunity arose just before planned: my husband received a proposal to work in a city where there was exactly the master&rsquo;s degree subject I was looking for. We got married in Brazil on April 14, 2018, according to our original schedule, and flew to Munich, Germany, four days after the wedding, arriving there on April 19, 2018.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Found a passion for mentoring</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/passion_mentoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/passion_mentoring/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="promoting-innovation-and-entrepreneurship">Promoting innovation and entrepreneurship&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A friend of mine who was also a former co-worker invited me to mentor in the &amp;ldquo;financial week&amp;rdquo; of a startup acceleration program&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>. I was very excited to have this opportunity to share knowledge and support the local startup ecosystem. As it couldn&amp;rsquo;t be different, my engagement went beyond that week. I became part of the examining board, judging the various early-stage startups, their businesses and their financial projections.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="promoting-innovation-and-entrepreneurship">Promoting innovation and entrepreneurship</h2>
<p>A friend of mine who was also a former co-worker invited me to mentor in the &ldquo;financial week&rdquo; of a startup acceleration program<sup>1</sup>. I was very excited to have this opportunity to share knowledge and support the local startup ecosystem. As it couldn&rsquo;t be different, my engagement went beyond that week. I became part of the examining board, judging the various early-stage startups, their businesses and their financial projections.</p>
<p>The next edition of the program took place in the same year and gained a different format and new sponsors. I participated in giving support in all possible topics, such as market introduction and strategic planning.</p>
<p>At that time, other acceleration programs invited me to give talks at events that they organized to promote innovation and entrepreneurship.</p>
<br/>
<script type="text/javascript" src="/js/lightbox.js"></script>
<link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/lightbox.css">

<style>
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery li {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%;}
    .image-gallery li a {text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important; color: #777;}
    .image-gallery li a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery li a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
</style>


<ul class="image-gallery">
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Launch_01_hu_e451ae7929617743.JPG" title="Launch_01" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Launch_01_hu_a04e1a84a4fa61ea.JPG" alt="Launch_01" title="Launch_01">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Launch_02_hu_e58f39424c498339.jpg" title="Launch_02" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Launch_02_hu_f207200548db3409.jpg" alt="Launch_02" title="Launch_02">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Launch_03_hu_9a08ed42c5472e40.jpg" title="Launch_03" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Launch_03_hu_d6fa965d33335529.jpg" alt="Launch_03" title="Launch_03">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Lemonade_01_hu_a15e514979c5c3da.jpg" title="Lemonade_01" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Lemonade_01_hu_68838938e4eec689.jpg" alt="Lemonade_01" title="Lemonade_01">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Lemonade_02_hu_2047559870584fc4.jpg" title="Lemonade_02" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Lemonade_02_hu_178903d8aac057eb.jpg" alt="Lemonade_02" title="Lemonade_02">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Lemonade_03_hu_2353bf0fffa91283.jpg" title="Lemonade_03" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Lemonade_03_hu_18dfadf57700d560.jpg" alt="Lemonade_03" title="Lemonade_03">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Talk_hu_b349d67bc78eb5e5.JPG" title="Talk" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/lemonade/Talk_hu_6b635e6ce6bf7dfe.JPG" alt="Talk" title="Talk">
    </a>
  </li>  

</ul>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="http://programalemonade.com.br/">Programa Lemonade</a> is an eight-week startup acceleration program in which selected teams receive entrepreneurial training with free content, lectures, mentoring, workshops and evaluation boards.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Enrolled in an English school</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_english/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_english/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="english-in-brazil">English in Brazil&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In Latin America, Brazilians are the only ones who speak Portuguese. Even though we are surrounded by countries that have Spanish as their mother tongue, we do not have a second official language. It may be the reason why there&amp;rsquo;s no incentive to learn another language. In the second part of elementary education in public schools, English is mandatory, but it does not go beyond the basics. Unfortunately, taking an English course privately is something that does not fit the budget of most Brazilians.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="english-in-brazil">English in Brazil</h2>
<p>In Latin America, Brazilians are the only ones who speak Portuguese. Even though we are surrounded by countries that have Spanish as their mother tongue, we do not have a second official language. It may be the reason why there&rsquo;s no incentive to learn another language. In the second part of elementary education in public schools, English is mandatory, but it does not go beyond the basics. Unfortunately, taking an English course privately is something that does not fit the budget of most Brazilians.</p>
<h2 id="my-turn-has-come">My turn has come</h2>
<p>I only had the chance to study English at a specialized school<sup>1</sup> at the age of 26, at the end of 2016. Before, all the knowledge of English that I had was acquired in a self-taught way, with resources that were tangible to me, such as music and readings. I also learned a lot at my first job, in 2005, when I worked at a translation company. Grasping every opportunity on my path took me to the intermediate level, but it wasn’t good enough to give me confidence when speaking.</p>
<p>I completed the course in 18 months, moving from intermediate to advanced level.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://wiseup.com/">Wise Up</a> is an English school that focuses on teaching English to adults.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Got an MBA in Finance</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/postgraduate_mba/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/postgraduate_mba/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-opportune-time">The opportune time&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I had been pursuing an MBA since I was about to finish college. However, it only became possible three years later, which I can say was even better due to the professional and personal maturity that I had acquired so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even amid a swirl of things to manage in my &lt;a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/startup_sympla/">current job&lt;/a>, getting an MBA in Finance represented an appropriate personal decision. The skills that I learned and improved perfectly fit the needs I had to fulfil in the scenario the company I was working for was in, especially during its M&amp;amp;A (mergers and acquisitions) processes, which was something that I was leading and doing for the very first time.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-opportune-time">The opportune time</h2>
<p>I had been pursuing an MBA since I was about to finish college. However, it only became possible three years later, which I can say was even better due to the professional and personal maturity that I had acquired so far.</p>
<p>Even amid a swirl of things to manage in my <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/startup_sympla/">current job</a>, getting an MBA in Finance represented an appropriate personal decision. The skills that I learned and improved perfectly fit the needs I had to fulfil in the scenario the company I was working for was in, especially during its M&amp;A (mergers and acquisitions) processes, which was something that I was leading and doing for the very first time.</p>
<h2 id="the-youngest-student">The youngest student</h2>
<p>I started an MBA in Finance at IBMEC (Brazilian Institute of Capital Markets)<sup>1</sup>, a reference school in finance and business in the country. After passing the selection process, I became the youngest student in my class. According to the school&rsquo;s coordinator, my professional experience was adequate and would be an enriching exchange of knowledge in the classroom.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.ibmec.br/english">Instituto Brasileiro de Mercado de Capitais</a> (IBMEC) is a private Brazilian research university founded in 1970. It is one of the most prestigious business and economics schools in Latin America.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Started working at Sympla</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/startup_sympla/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/startup_sympla/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="from-the-ground-up">From the ground up&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This experience gave me an incredible opportunity to make a difference! I was the Financial Manager and Team Leader of a successful startup, Sympla&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>, an online platform for sale and management of tickets and registration for events. I worked there for four years, since the embryonic stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first time I met Rodrigo Cartacho, the CEO, was special. It was on this memorable occasion that I, full of enthusiasm, decided to dive right into the challenge of starting four departments from scratch. Rodrigo conducted one of the stages of the interview process, which took place on the balcony because, at that time, there was no meeting room. This small and simple detail became a milestone, as it represents how long the travelled road was when the starting point for me was a room with a meeting room under construction and four newly hired employees – the very first ones – and the destination was almost the entire building occupied and more than 200 employees working on. More than that, we have transformed a start-up into the company with the largest number of events for sale in Brazil. It meant a lot of work and concerted effort by the entire team, and pride and joy, consequently.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="from-the-ground-up">From the ground up</h2>
<p>This experience gave me an incredible opportunity to make a difference! I was the Financial Manager and Team Leader of a successful startup, Sympla<sup>1</sup>, an online platform for sale and management of tickets and registration for events. I worked there for four years, since the embryonic stage.</p>
<p>The first time I met Rodrigo Cartacho, the CEO, was special. It was on this memorable occasion that I, full of enthusiasm, decided to dive right into the challenge of starting four departments from scratch. Rodrigo conducted one of the stages of the interview process, which took place on the balcony because, at that time, there was no meeting room. This small and simple detail became a milestone, as it represents how long the travelled road was when the starting point for me was a room with a meeting room under construction and four newly hired employees – the very first ones – and the destination was almost the entire building occupied and more than 200 employees working on. More than that, we have transformed a start-up into the company with the largest number of events for sale in Brazil. It meant a lot of work and concerted effort by the entire team, and pride and joy, consequently.</p>
<h2 id="challenges-bring-them-on">Challenges? Bring them on!</h2>
<p>During the first year, I led and structured the financial, administrative, human resources and personnel departments. The second year was a moment of transition in which I had to hand over control of the various cards I was holding in a scenario of significant company growth where I had only one intern to support me. Therefore, I expanded my team as well as selected and hired people to run those three latter departments. Then, I finally was able to focus on the finance department, bringing even more improvements. Many projects, challenges and changes have emerged in the following two years.</p>
<h2 id="recognition">Recognition</h2>
<p>At length, when I decided to end this period of my career to take a break and follow my way living abroad, I left a company 50 times bigger than when I started, with 5 more offices in 5 different cities and nationally recognized as the market leader; two completed due diligence that resulted in two investments made by a global leader in mobile marketplaces; a management software (SAP) implemented and designed to integrate all operations; innumerable procedures developed and good practices applied; and last but not least, a brilliant and loyal financial team to continue the work of ensuring the company’s financial stability and growth.</p>
<br/>
<script type="text/javascript" src="/js/lightbox.js"></script>
<link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/lightbox.css">

<style>
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery li {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%;}
    .image-gallery li a {text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important; color: #777;}
    .image-gallery li a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery li a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
</style>


<ul class="image-gallery">
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/All_01_hu_bf934f253726e85b.jpg" title="All_01" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/All_01_hu_f8a8936fdcebe2e7.jpg" alt="All_01" title="All_01">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/All_02_hu_2531f47ce98e9679.jpg" title="All_02" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/All_02_hu_89097c973c114d53.jpg" alt="All_02" title="All_02">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/CASE_01_hu_dd176fa8637ebbd9.jpg" title="CASE_01" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/CASE_01_hu_c9750a8d01780706.jpg" alt="CASE_01" title="CASE_01">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/CASE_02_hu_ca502d1b2eb1035b.jpg" title="CASE_02" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/CASE_02_hu_6fc819a56d8612e3.jpg" alt="CASE_02" title="CASE_02">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/Movile_hu_be8cb01294a767ff.jpg" title="Movile" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/Movile_hu_bd2a37c2e855c42a.jpg" alt="Movile" title="Movile">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/Sympla_eu_hu_b313dc75b28e60e4.jpg" title="Sympla_eu" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/Sympla_eu_hu_65fdf483ef00f4f0.jpg" alt="Sympla_eu" title="Sympla_eu">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/Team_01_hu_8d2871da6dcba36d.jpeg" title="Team_01" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/Team_01_hu_acefb7d6ad1b1062.jpeg" alt="Team_01" title="Team_01">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/Team_02_hu_3a31607909c959d8.jpeg" title="Team_02" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/Team_02_hu_f4b271c740f1871f.jpeg" alt="Team_02" title="Team_02">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/Team_03_hu_28c57c6609f787b9.JPG" title="Team_03" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/sympla/Team_03_hu_fc1815dbe3bf19be.JPG" alt="Team_03" title="Team_03">
    </a>
  </li>  

</ul>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.sympla.com.br">Sympla</a> is Brazil&rsquo;s leading self-service ticketing and event management platform. The company has been created to empower event organizers by providing them with a complete set of tools that facilitate ticket selling and managing each stage of their events.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Got the first job as a Manager</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/manager_first/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/manager_first/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="audit-and-consultancy-phase">Audit and consultancy phase&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What was supposed to be only an audit led me to my first job as a financial manager. I was approached by one of the partners to do an independent audit of their company&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>, including assets and debts since its inception. Within a month, the CEO asked for a blueprint of what would be an ideal finance department.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to the audit, I built the finance department, its processes and routine from scratch; created the job description, selected and hired a person to do the basics tasks – an assistant – and get the department started. At the end of the audit and consultancy, the CEO, who longed for a more organized company, with well-defined planning and procedures, invited me to work alongside him to restructure it. So, I assumed the role of Manager of the finance, administrative and human resources departments.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="audit-and-consultancy-phase">Audit and consultancy phase</h2>
<p>What was supposed to be only an audit led me to my first job as a financial manager. I was approached by one of the partners to do an independent audit of their company<sup>1</sup>, including assets and debts since its inception. Within a month, the CEO asked for a blueprint of what would be an ideal finance department.</p>
<p>In addition to the audit, I built the finance department, its processes and routine from scratch; created the job description, selected and hired a person to do the basics tasks – an assistant – and get the department started. At the end of the audit and consultancy, the CEO, who longed for a more organized company, with well-defined planning and procedures, invited me to work alongside him to restructure it. So, I assumed the role of Manager of the finance, administrative and human resources departments.</p>
<h2 id="management-phase">Management phase</h2>
<p>Changes such as policies, controls, and processes implementation caused tough resistance from employees. However, as tough as this resistance were my patience and persistence in being transparent and presenting each change clearly, explaining what/why/how/when it should be applied. In a few weeks, I gained their trust and, more than that, their support. I considered it as a triumph during my first time managing a team. In this case, a multidisciplinary team of 8 people.</p>
<p>Besides the restructuring project, I designed and implemented the operating flow of the new revenue stream, starting another department from scratch: a sales one. Once again, I built and implemented procedures, controls, and routines, as well as hiring the team and organizing their training. The sales surpassed expectations, representing about 80% of all revenue in less than a year.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100072242684815">Vinte1</a> is a Brazilian company that offers services of project management, planning and event production.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Founded my own business</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/own_business/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/own_business/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="quatrenhum-events">Quatrenhum Events&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Quatrenhum&lt;/em> was a small business directed by myself and a partner. We provided an on-demand service of selected and highly qualified teams of promoters focused on the promotion of brands, products, services, campaigns and sales.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="an-idea-was-born">An idea was born&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I identified a pain point in the operation of promotional marketing companies as a market opportunity while freelancing for them. I participated in all stages of the operation in two or three companies and realized that they could all do better. So, I decided to solve this pain point by creating a solution that was a scalable business. As this market was not my area of expertise, I invited a friend to fill this gap and be my business partner.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="quatrenhum-events">Quatrenhum Events</h2>
<p><em>Quatrenhum</em> was a small business directed by myself and a partner. We provided an on-demand service of selected and highly qualified teams of promoters focused on the promotion of brands, products, services, campaigns and sales.</p>
<h2 id="an-idea-was-born">An idea was born</h2>
<p>I identified a pain point in the operation of promotional marketing companies as a market opportunity while freelancing for them. I participated in all stages of the operation in two or three companies and realized that they could all do better. So, I decided to solve this pain point by creating a solution that was a scalable business. As this market was not my area of expertise, I invited a friend to fill this gap and be my business partner.</p>
<h2 id="market-introduction">Market introduction</h2>
<p>After creating and validating the business model as scalable and profitable, we started to run the business by presenting a highly qualified team to the market to promote their brand, with a high standard of performance guaranteed. We created a platform for registering and managing promoters that gained popularity in a few weeks. Our competitive edge and the pain point solution was: in every promotional marketing activity, we nominated a supervisor to ensure that the team made an excellent delivery based on the high-quality training we set. It did not represent extra costs for the customer.</p>
<p>It worked well. The market started to notice us and spread the happy word. As a result, we got most of our clients by word-of-mouth recommendations.</p>
<h2 id="the-end">The end</h2>
<p>Without an office, this bootstrapping business ran for four years until its closure, which was done by mutual decision. While running it, I was building my career in the financial field. Consequently, my dedication and focus were most directed to Finance. In 2016, I faced the prioritization process that led me to decide to close <em>Quatrenhum</em>.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Alternated a new job with consulting activity</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/alternated_jobs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/alternated_jobs/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="spinning-plates">Spinning plates&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I set high expectations for my first job after college, which I agreed to start from scratch on an unusual program at a car dealership&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>. This program assigned me to do elementary tasks as a way to acquaint myself with all subdivisions in the finance department. That way, I would know all the processes, their strengths and weaknesses, which would enable me to reach a leadership position in a short period of time.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="spinning-plates">Spinning plates</h2>
<p>I set high expectations for my first job after college, which I agreed to start from scratch on an unusual program at a car dealership<sup>1</sup>. This program assigned me to do elementary tasks as a way to acquaint myself with all subdivisions in the finance department. That way, I would know all the processes, their strengths and weaknesses, which would enable me to reach a leadership position in a short period of time.</p>
<p>Alternately, I was working as an independent consultant, including advising friends&rsquo; businesses. Thinking outside the box led me to draft my own business.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="http://bordeaux-bh.com.br">Bordeaux Veículos</a> is a Peugeot dealership based in Belo Horizonte, Brazil. It sells new and used vehicles, as well as offering a variety of mechanical services.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Got the first projects as an Independent Consultant</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/first_consultancies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/first_consultancies/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="laying-the-groundwork">Laying the groundwork&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My experience as a financial advisor in 2010, during my internship at the University Extension Dean&amp;rsquo;s Office, made me realize how much I enjoy leading people to the understanding of their finances and the results of their business strategies. So, as soon as I finished college, I became a member of the Regional Business Administration Council&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup> to validate the recognition of my profession and also to give authenticity to any independent work I did.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="laying-the-groundwork">Laying the groundwork</h2>
<p>My experience as a financial advisor in 2010, during my internship at the University Extension Dean&rsquo;s Office, made me realize how much I enjoy leading people to the understanding of their finances and the results of their business strategies. So, as soon as I finished college, I became a member of the Regional Business Administration Council<sup>1</sup> to validate the recognition of my profession and also to give authenticity to any independent work I did.</p>
<h2 id="first-projects">First projects</h2>
<p>I spent two months delved into my first consultancy as an independent professional. The owners of an engineering company had an important decision to make, which could culminate in its voluntary dissolution. Knowing the current financial situation would be crucial in this process. An audit of accounts and an examination of tax, financial and accounting documents were the essential starting point. As a result, I presented a final financial report showing how the company was being managed, the composition of its costs, debts and forecasts.</p>
<p>In late 2011, another project emerged, in which the consultancy was focused on improving its financial management and inventory control processes.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="cramg.org.br">Conselho Regional de Administração de Minas</a> (CRA-MG) is a normative, consultative, advisory and disciplinary Brazilian entity for the exercise of the profession, based in each region of the country, responsible for controlling and inspecting financial and administrative activities.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Graduated with Honour</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/graduated_honour/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/graduated_honour/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="mission-accomplished">Mission accomplished&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As is customary in Brazil, the person who graduates with the highest overall grade throughout the undergraduate program is announced at the Graduation Ceremony and honoured with a medal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was wearing a graduation gown and, along with my classmates, attending the graduation ceremony when a professor came to announce the student with the best grades in our class. My friends were already staring at me, and my family was saying my name a few seconds before the professor named it. In that fraction of time, I just took a deep breath and remembered how much I dedicated myself to be the first person in my family to graduate from a University; how hard I worked to be there; how many nights studying to recover the time that I spent in an office, working, while other students could only focus on studying; how proud I was of myself&amp;hellip; and then, my name was called! Applause and shouting were the soundtracks that pushed me to the stage to be honoured. In that night, I was awarded a Golden Medal of Honour for outstanding performance throughout the Financial Management program at the Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais.&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="mission-accomplished">Mission accomplished</h2>
<p>As is customary in Brazil, the person who graduates with the highest overall grade throughout the undergraduate program is announced at the Graduation Ceremony and honoured with a medal.</p>
<p>I was wearing a graduation gown and, along with my classmates, attending the graduation ceremony when a professor came to announce the student with the best grades in our class. My friends were already staring at me, and my family was saying my name a few seconds before the professor named it. In that fraction of time, I just took a deep breath and remembered how much I dedicated myself to be the first person in my family to graduate from a University; how hard I worked to be there; how many nights studying to recover the time that I spent in an office, working, while other students could only focus on studying; how proud I was of myself&hellip; and then, my name was called! Applause and shouting were the soundtracks that pushed me to the stage to be honoured. In that night, I was awarded a Golden Medal of Honour for outstanding performance throughout the Financial Management program at the Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais.<sup>1</sup></p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.pucminas.br/destaques/Paginas/default.aspx">Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais</a> (PUC Minas) is a private and non-profit Brazilian Catholic university. Recently, the Congregation for Catholic Education of the Vatican chose the Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, PUC Minas, as the largest in the world.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Completed the internship season</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/ended_internshipseason/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/ended_internshipseason/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="closing-a-cycle">Closing a cycle&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I can say that it was hard to close this cycle, especially due to my deep involvement with at least two social projects while working at the University&amp;rsquo;s Dean of Extension. I really wanted to continue this work for the next semester, and so did my supervisor and the team. However, I had to turn over a new leaf. I embraced the feeling of fulfilment and accepted that I did my best while I could. I recommended a worthy friend to replace me and give as much love and dedication as I did. I had a personal situation to face and move on.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="closing-a-cycle">Closing a cycle</h2>
<p>I can say that it was hard to close this cycle, especially due to my deep involvement with at least two social projects while working at the University&rsquo;s Dean of Extension. I really wanted to continue this work for the next semester, and so did my supervisor and the team. However, I had to turn over a new leaf. I embraced the feeling of fulfilment and accepted that I did my best while I could. I recommended a worthy friend to replace me and give as much love and dedication as I did. I had a personal situation to face and move on.</p>
<h2 id="started-to-work-at-tutta">Started to work at Tutta¹</h2>
<p>Working full time during my final year of college was challenging. On the other hand, it was a great chance to consolidate the knowledge acquired so far. I started working in the office of a fashion company where I was responsible for supporting the financial routine of all payments and receipts, as well as for the budget and composition of production costs. In addition, I supported the industrial production team in the management of materials logistics and optimization of the production process through the PPC (Production Planning and Control) methodology, for which I received adequate training to develop the necessary skills.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://loja.tutta.com.br/">Tutta</a> is a Brazilian fashion couture brand specialized in party dresses aimed at the luxury segment.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Invited to be part of the University Extension Program team</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/extension_internship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/extension_internship/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-invitation">The invitation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since mid-2009, I have been involved in project extensions at the University&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>, either working actively as a volunteer or researching my thesis. When I received an invitation to be part of the extension programs department&lt;sup>2&lt;/sup>, I was pretty excited and proud of myself. That meant that my dedication was notorious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A professor specialized in finance became my supervisor to guide me in my main task of advising solidarity economy ventures.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-invitation">The invitation</h2>
<p>Since mid-2009, I have been involved in project extensions at the University<sup>1</sup>, either working actively as a volunteer or researching my thesis. When I received an invitation to be part of the extension programs department<sup>2</sup>, I was pretty excited and proud of myself. That meant that my dedication was notorious.</p>
<p>A professor specialized in finance became my supervisor to guide me in my main task of advising solidarity economy ventures.</p>
<h2 id="university-incubator-project">University Incubator Project</h2>
<p>The University Incubator Project was a cooperative venture for processing natural food into dehydrated food. In 2005, an agreement was signed between the Government, the mayor’s office and the University for the development of this solidarity economy pilot project. I joined the team in 2009, when the physical facilities were completed, to meet the lack of operational procedures and promote governance practices.</p>
<p>I worked with groups of housewives, unemployed women and beneficiaries of a Federal Government Program. They formed this cooperative venture as associates. As the main objective of the project was administrative emancipation, they were learning to be owners of their own business through the solidarity economy methodology. I acted as a facilitating agent between these associates and some institutions when dealing with bureaucracy. Moreover, I applied my knowledge in finance to support them in managing the business, advising and giving a full consultancy.</p>
<h2 id="solidarity-economy">Solidarity Economy</h2>
<p>The crisis of capitalism and its inherent worsening of poverty has led to the emergence of different modes of production. One is the solidarity economy that emerged to serve the population excluded from the formal labour market. Thus, people from a local community such as artisans, for example, come together and work collectively and associatively, using solidarity principles in which one collaborates with the other. Equitable income distribution eliminates labour exploitation. Relations with other partners are also based on a solidarity economy, which makes trade fair.</p>
<h2 id="highlights">Highlights</h2>
<ul>
<li>The work of fostering financial education in the incubator was so successful that I travelled to the countryside as a representative of the Dean of Extension to give talks to local producers and small cooperatives. These talks were open to discussion in order to address the participants&rsquo; issues and develop consultancy for building a solidarity venture.</li>
<li>I researched the solidarity economy during the period in which I worked in the incubator and continued researching after the internship ended. I used this experience to write my thesis, which aimed to show that a solidarity enterprise can be economically and financially viable.</li>
<li>Working in the extension programs department led me to be even more active as a volunteer, especially in social projects. The one that I dedicated the most was the <a href="https://www.gov.br/defesa/pt-br/assuntos/projeto-rondon">Rondon Project</a>, the largest university volunteer initiative in Brazil.</li>
</ul>
<br/>
<script type="text/javascript" src="/js/lightbox.js"></script>
<link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/lightbox.css">

<style>
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery li {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%;}
    .image-gallery li a {text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important; color: #777;}
    .image-gallery li a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery li a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
</style>


<ul class="image-gallery">
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/puc/Rondon_01_hu_4c14cf8219bb7bb.jpeg" title="Rondon_01" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/puc/Rondon_01_hu_9a952eb61807f783.jpeg" alt="Rondon_01" title="Rondon_01">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/puc/Rondon_02_hu_21a81fa3519c4e76.jpeg" title="Rondon_02" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/puc/Rondon_02_hu_3e653cb86ef6a2df.jpeg" alt="Rondon_02" title="Rondon_02">
    </a>
  </li>  
<li>
    <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/puc/Talk_hu_da1af78ece79b434.jpeg" title="Talk" class="lightbox-image">
      <img src="https://micanogueira.github.io/pictures/puc/Talk_hu_33bdeaca0b4750a9.jpeg" alt="Talk" title="Talk">
    </a>
  </li>  

</ul>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.pucminas.br/destaques/Paginas/default.aspx">Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais</a> (PUC Minas) is a private and non-profit Brazilian Catholic university. Recently, the Congregation for Catholic Education of the Vatican chose the Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, PUC Minas, as the largest in the world.</small><br/>
<small><sup>2</sup> <a href="http://www.pucminas.br/proex">PROEX</a> is the Dean of Extension that plans, coordinates and executes extension activities at the University, and promotes agreements and partnerships to enable projects for university interaction with the community.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Became coordinator of a University Extension Program</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/coordinator_extension/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/coordinator_extension/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="engagement">Engagement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As soon as my second year of college&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup> started, I tried to remain engaged in extracurricular activities. I was invited by the same professor with whom I worked in the &lt;a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/engaged_extension/">previous extension program&lt;/a> to be the coordinator of a new extension program he had submitted to the University. I volunteered to lead the &amp;ldquo;Student - University - Society Integration Program&amp;rdquo; project, which aimed to advocate for education and strengthen the university&amp;rsquo;s mission by providing training to students and encouraging their interchange with teachers, staff, classmates, and community.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="engagement">Engagement</h2>
<p>As soon as my second year of college<sup>1</sup> started, I tried to remain engaged in extracurricular activities. I was invited by the same professor with whom I worked in the <a href="https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/engaged_extension/">previous extension program</a> to be the coordinator of a new extension program he had submitted to the University.  I volunteered to lead the &ldquo;Student - University - Society Integration Program&rdquo; project, which aimed to advocate for education and strengthen the university&rsquo;s mission by providing training to students and encouraging their interchange with teachers, staff, classmates, and community.</p>
<h2 id="the-extension-program">The extension program</h2>
<p>The initial kick-off of the project was to develop its theoretical framework; in other words, to develop the methodology and research to show the team and other partners what methods would be used. The next step was to compose the team. So the teacher and I selected the other volunteers. In this first stage of the project, we conducted focus group interviews with teachers from different programs to diagnose what the main problems were in the social relations between employees, teachers and students. We also conducted these focus group interviews with students, also from different programs.</p>
<p>At the end of the semester, I presented the project and its current results at the Extension Workshop at the University.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.pucminas.br/destaques/Paginas/default.aspx">Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais</a> (PUC Minas) is a private and non-profit Brazilian Catholic university. Recently, the Congregation for Catholic Education of the Vatican chose the Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, PUC Minas, as the largest in the world.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Started a financial internship</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/financial_internship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/financial_internship/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="from-classes-to-office-hands-on-experience">From classes to office: hands-on experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since I became the teaching assistant of the Financial Mathematics discipline of the Financial Management program, I wanted to bring vivid experiences into the classroom. Therefore, I also became an intern at an engineering company&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My interest in learning to apply those maths in a real environment drove me to assume so many responsibilities that I ended up replacing my supervisor for a month. For the first time, I could operate the entire financial routine of a company, including cash flow control and bank negotiations.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="from-classes-to-office-hands-on-experience">From classes to office: hands-on experience</h2>
<p>Since I became the teaching assistant of the Financial Mathematics discipline of the Financial Management program, I wanted to bring vivid experiences into the classroom. Therefore, I also became an intern at an engineering company<sup>1</sup>.</p>
<p>My interest in learning to apply those maths in a real environment drove me to assume so many responsibilities that I ended up replacing my supervisor for a month. For the first time, I could operate the entire financial routine of a company, including cash flow control and bank negotiations.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> GSM Engenharia is a Brazilian company specialized in developing projects and budgets for civil construction.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Started teaching a new discipline</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/new_discipline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/new_discipline/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="new-semester-more-knowledge-to-share">New semester, more knowledge to share&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I found great joy in teaching other classes and showing them different ways to learn and improve their skills. For that reason, at the beginning of my second year of college&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>, I decided to continue being a teaching assistant but in a new discipline. Therefore, I became the teaching assistant of the Financial Mathematics discipline of the Financial Management program.&lt;/p>
&lt;br/>
&lt;br/>
&lt;p>&lt;small>&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup> &lt;a href="https://www.pucminas.br/destaques/Paginas/default.aspx">Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais&lt;/a> (PUC Minas) is a private and non-profit Brazilian Catholic university. Recently, the Congregation for Catholic Education of the Vatican chose the Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, PUC Minas, as the largest in the world. &lt;/small>&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="new-semester-more-knowledge-to-share">New semester, more knowledge to share</h2>
<p>I found great joy in teaching other classes and showing them different ways to learn and improve their skills. For that reason, at the beginning of my second year of college<sup>1</sup>, I decided to continue being a teaching assistant but in a new discipline. Therefore, I became the teaching assistant of the Financial Mathematics discipline of the Financial Management program.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.pucminas.br/destaques/Paginas/default.aspx">Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais</a> (PUC Minas) is a private and non-profit Brazilian Catholic university. Recently, the Congregation for Catholic Education of the Vatican chose the Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, PUC Minas, as the largest in the world. </small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Started an accounting internship</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/accounting_internship/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/accounting_internship/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="exploring-the-accounting-field">Exploring the accounting field&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the end of my first year of college, while I became the teaching assistant of the Introduction to Accounting discipline of the Financial Management program, I found a great opportunity to explore beyond classes and learn how an accounting office works. So, in addition to teaching, I became an intern at a company&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup> that provides survey services to the mining, gas and oil, and groundwater industries. For the first time, I worked with an integrated system as well as with the analysis of financial indexes, account reconciliation, and a variety of taxes.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="exploring-the-accounting-field">Exploring the accounting field</h2>
<p>At the end of my first year of college, while I became the teaching assistant of the Introduction to Accounting discipline of the Financial Management program, I found a great opportunity to explore beyond classes and learn how an accounting office works. So, in addition to teaching, I became an intern at a company<sup>1</sup> that provides survey services to the mining, gas and oil, and groundwater industries. For the first time, I worked with an integrated system as well as with the analysis of financial indexes, account reconciliation, and a variety of taxes.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> Georadar is a Brazilian company specialized in providing onshore and offshore geophysical, geotechnical and environmental surveys.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Found a passion for teaching</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/passion_teaching/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/passion_teaching/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-passion">The passion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In fact, that passion has always been there, hidden in my guts. When I was only six to seven years old, in my first year of school, I had my first experience teaching. I supported the class teacher by helping my peers learn to read. I was timid at that time, but sitting next to someone else and teaching reading and writing was very natural. In the following years of elementary school, I created lessons and printed them out for the class to do as homework. It was like I was a very young teaching assistant.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-passion">The passion</h2>
<p>In fact, that passion has always been there, hidden in my guts. When I was only six to seven years old, in my first year of school, I had my first experience teaching. I supported the class teacher by helping my peers learn to read. I was timid at that time, but sitting next to someone else and teaching reading and writing was very natural. In the following years of elementary school, I created lessons and printed them out for the class to do as homework. It was like I was a very young teaching assistant.</p>
<h2 id="becoming-a-teaching-assistant">Becoming a Teaching Assistant</h2>
<p>Students with high marks in a given discipline can apply to be a teaching assistant of that discipline. Right in the first year of college<sup>1</sup>, I became one. In my second semester (in Brazil, the colleges have two terms that we call semester or period), I started teaching the subject of Introduction to Accounting in the 2/2009 class of the Financial Management program.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.pucminas.br/destaques/Paginas/default.aspx">Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais</a> (PUC Minas) is a private and non-profit Brazilian Catholic university. Recently, the Congregation for Catholic Education of the Vatican chose the Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, PUC Minas, as the largest in the world.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Engaged in University Extension Programs</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/engaged_extension/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/engaged_extension/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="roots">Roots&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Throughout my school life, I was involved in extracurricular activities such as choir, student council, newspaper, theatre, and dance. I used to extend my hours at school, supporting teachers and diverse staff members. I had often been a class representative. Sometimes, a commencement speaker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I entered college&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>, it was no different. In the first year, I already found myself involved in an extracurricular activity: extension programs. I volunteered to support the &amp;ldquo;Census and Citizenship&amp;rdquo; project, which aimed to diagnose the community&amp;rsquo;s socio-economic situation in order to highlight and prioritize their needs.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="roots">Roots</h2>
<p>Throughout my school life, I was involved in extracurricular activities such as choir, student council, newspaper, theatre, and dance. I used to extend my hours at school, supporting teachers and diverse staff members. I had often been a class representative. Sometimes, a commencement speaker.</p>
<p>When I entered college<sup>1</sup>, it was no different. In the first year, I already found myself involved in an extracurricular activity: extension programs. I volunteered to support the &ldquo;Census and Citizenship&rdquo; project, which aimed to diagnose the community&rsquo;s socio-economic situation in order to highlight and prioritize their needs.</p>
<h2 id="the-extension-program">The extension program</h2>
<p>A multidisciplinary team composed of students from three different programs was organized to work together to achieve that objective. We interviewed people who lived near the campus. My group and I focused on interviewing people who lived in a building complex nearby. We collected information about basic needs, such as eating habits, health, education, social, and leisure. Apart from the teamwork, I was also responsible for data tabulation.</p>
<p>At the end of our work, we were able to make a diagnosis, identify the community&rsquo;s demand and propose actions through new extension programs.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.pucminas.br/destaques/Paginas/default.aspx">Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais</a> (PUC Minas) is a private and non-profit Brazilian Catholic university. Recently, the Congregation for Catholic Education of the Vatican chose the Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, PUC Minas, as the largest in the world.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Returned to work at the company where got the first job</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/back_origins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/back_origins/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="heading">&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;The good son always returns home&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I was invited to work again (once in 2006) on the company&amp;rsquo;s&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup> main project, AVRO dx, an unabridged online English-Portuguese-English Dictionary. This time, temporarily, reviewing the formatting and testing the platform as an end-user. Besides, I supported the administrative team with a focus on financial routine and customer service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being a QA tester came very naturally to me, although I had never played that role before. Working with the IT team, I contributed to the platform usage by reporting issues and requesting features, which turned into great improvements. Consequently, an open communication channel emerged between IT and other co-workers who also wanted to contribute.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="heading"><em>&ldquo;The good son always returns home&rdquo;</em></h2>
<p>I was invited to work again (once in 2006) on the company&rsquo;s<sup>1</sup> main project, AVRO dx, an unabridged online English-Portuguese-English Dictionary. This time, temporarily, reviewing the formatting and testing the platform as an end-user. Besides, I supported the administrative team with a focus on financial routine and customer service.</p>
<p>Being a QA tester came very naturally to me, although I had never played that role before. Working with the IT team, I contributed to the platform usage by reporting issues and requesting features, which turned into great improvements. Consequently, an open communication channel emerged between IT and other co-workers who also wanted to contribute.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> AVRO is an Brazilian-based translation company.</small><br>
<small><em>To know more about AVROdx click on this link: <a href="https://www.avro.com.br/#avrodx">www.avro.com.br/#avrodx</a></em></small><br/>
<small><em>And click <a href="http://editor.avrodx.com.br/about/credits">here</a> to check the credits attributed to me as a contributing editor</em></small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Won a scholarship to College</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/won_scholarship2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/won_scholarship2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I received a high score in the national entrance exam (known as &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exame_Nacional_do_Ensino_M%C3%A9dio">ENEM&lt;/a> in Brazil), which made me eligible to win a scholarship to college. I was selected by the best private university&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup> in the country and ranked third in the list of those admitted to its Financial Management program.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="managing-expectations">Managing expectations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since the beginning of my second year of high school, while working in a bank in parallel, my dream was to study economics. I aimed at the Federal University, which offered a recognizable program in economics. This dream lasted the two years I had to finish high school. During a vocational test and visit to the Federal University, I discovered that the classes would be in the morning and afternoon. This important information shattered my dream because working was a matter of necessity for me. I had to work to study, to pay for basic expenses such as academic books, transportation and food. I couldn’t afford to study on a shift other than at night.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I received a high score in the national entrance exam (known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exame_Nacional_do_Ensino_M%C3%A9dio">ENEM</a> in Brazil), which made me eligible to win a scholarship to college. I was selected by the best private university<sup>1</sup> in the country and ranked third in the list of those admitted to its Financial Management program.</p>
<h2 id="managing-expectations">Managing expectations</h2>
<p>Since the beginning of my second year of high school, while working in a bank in parallel, my dream was to study economics. I aimed at the Federal University, which offered a recognizable program in economics. This dream lasted the two years I had to finish high school. During a vocational test and visit to the Federal University, I discovered that the classes would be in the morning and afternoon. This important information shattered my dream because working was a matter of necessity for me. I had to work to study, to pay for basic expenses such as academic books, transportation and food. I couldn’t afford to study on a shift other than at night.</p>
<p>In summary, I had to be realistic and find a program related to economics, where classes were taught on the night shift. Besides, developing skills that helped me find a balance between work and study remained my number one day-to-day task.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.pucminas.br/destaques/Paginas/default.aspx">Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais</a> (PUC Minas) is a private and non-profit Brazilian Catholic university. Recently, the Congregation for Catholic Education of the Vatican chose the Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, PUC Minas, as the largest in the world.</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Started an internship at a Federal Bank</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/internship_bank/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/internship_bank/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="inspiration-moves-us-brightly">Inspiration moves us brightly!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I met Andrea for the first time in my interview, when she pointed to the desk and said: “You will work there if you pass this process”. I left the interview with a genuine smile on my face. I felt with all my heart that this internship vacancy would be mine. That is the most vivid and shiny memory I have of this experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andrea was my supervisor and also the manager of the sector where I worked at the bank&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>. More than that, she was my first female reference and inspiration for leadership. I admired so much the way she treated people equally, clients and coworkers, at any level, that I decided to follow her.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="inspiration-moves-us-brightly">Inspiration moves us brightly!</h2>
<p>I met Andrea for the first time in my interview, when she pointed to the desk and said: “You will work there if you pass this process”. I left the interview with a genuine smile on my face. I felt with all my heart that this internship vacancy would be mine. That is the most vivid and shiny memory I have of this experience.</p>
<p>Andrea was my supervisor and also the manager of the sector where I worked at the bank<sup>1</sup>. More than that, she was my first female reference and inspiration for leadership. I admired so much the way she treated people equally, clients and coworkers, at any level, that I decided to follow her.</p>
<p>My main task was to open bank accounts. In a few months, I managed to retain some customers, which broadened my customer service, allowing me to do more than the basics, such as selling financial products. With the knowledge and practice acquired, I took part in the onboarding and training processes of new employees, leading them during the first weeks of working directly with the client.</p>
<p>This experience led me to determine my career: study financial management at one of the best private colleges in the country, also by means of a scholarship.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://ri.caixa.gov.br/en/">Caixa Econômica Federal</a> (<em>Federal Savings Bank</em>, CEF or CAIXA) is a government-owned financial institution. It is Brazil’s third-largest bank by assets and the largest publicly held bank in Latin America. It plays a substantial role in the country’s development in the areas of housing, basic sanitation, infrastructure, and public services. </small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Won a scholarship</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/won_scholarship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/won_scholarship/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="contextualizing">Contextualizing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It all started when I heard the news that some private schools in my hometown were offering scholarships to high school students who couldn’t afford it. That caught my attention immediately. Admission to universities in Brazil requires students to sit a very competitive entrance exam known as &lt;em>vestibular&lt;/em>. Private high school students have a great advantage due to the high-quality education they receive. Besides, they can afford extra classes or preparatory courses for the entrance exam. At that time, all my studies had been completed in public school. Furthermore, financing a preparatory course was out of the question. The news really put me back on track to pursue higher education.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="contextualizing">Contextualizing</h2>
<p>It all started when I heard the news that some private schools in my hometown were offering scholarships to high school students who couldn’t afford it. That caught my attention immediately. Admission to universities in Brazil requires students to sit a very competitive entrance exam known as <em>vestibular</em>. Private high school students have a great advantage due to the high-quality education they receive. Besides, they can afford extra classes or preparatory courses for the entrance exam. At that time, all my studies had been completed in public school. Furthermore, financing a preparatory course was out of the question. The news really put me back on track to pursue higher education.</p>
<h2 id="pinning-all-my-hopes">Pinning all my hopes</h2>
<p>Ambitiously, I aimed my efforts at the best private high school<sup>1</sup> in the city. It held first place in the college admissions ranking for consecutive years.</p>
<p>After a social-economic interview, I was able to take the scholarship test. I was very confident on the day of the exam, but I must confess that when I saw hundreds of students in the gymnasium, my legs trembled. During the test, my pencil broke and I lost my eraser, which made me quite nervous. However, I returned home with a sense of accomplishment.</p>
<h2 id="i-did-it">I did it</h2>
<p>Weeks later, I was about to turn off my computer at my workstation when I decided to look up my name on the approved list. I remember this moment so vividly! When I scrolled a bit and found my name, I could barely believe it. I wanted to shout of joy, but I couldn’t because I was in the office. I felt so proud of myself. I was one of the twelve students who passed among the more than five hundred candidates.</p>
<p>I grasped an opportunity to study for two years at the best private school in the city as a way to prepare for the <em>vestibular</em>, increasing my chances of competing for a place in college.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> <a href="https://www.colegiosantoantonio.com.br/">Colégio Santo Antônio</a> (CSA) is a Brazilian Franciscan school that has been in operation for more than 100 years. In 2008, the educational institution won fourth place in Brazil in the High School Nacional Exam (ENEM). Ten years later, in 2018, the school became a member of the UNESCO Associated Schools Program Network (PEA / Unesco).</small></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Got the first job</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/first_job/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/first_job/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="it-started-even-before-it-started">It started even before it started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When I was fifteen years old, in late 2005, I came across an offer to learn to type. I did not have a computer at the time, but I was eager to learn, starting with the basics. Then, the founder of AVRO&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup> — a family’s friend — offered to teach it to me for an hour a day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within a few months, I was using the acquired abilities to help him in his ambitious project, AVRO dx, an unabridged online English-Portuguese-English Dictionary. I was informally organizing and formatting a copy of the database as a way to practice typing. When I realized, I was also reporting some errors and doing this job so quickly that he invited me to officially contribute to the project and work in the company as an assistant in administrative routines.&lt;/p></description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="it-started-even-before-it-started">It started even before it started</h2>
<p>When I was fifteen years old, in late 2005, I came across an offer to learn to type. I did not have a computer at the time, but I was eager to learn, starting with the basics. Then, the founder of AVRO<sup>1</sup> — a family’s friend — offered to teach it to me for an hour a day.</p>
<p>Within a few months, I was using the acquired abilities to help him in his ambitious project, AVRO dx, an unabridged online English-Portuguese-English Dictionary. I was informally organizing and formatting a copy of the database as a way to practice typing. When I realized, I was also reporting some errors and doing this job so quickly that he invited me to officially contribute to the project and work in the company as an assistant in administrative routines.</p>
<h2 id="lessons-learned">Lessons learned</h2>
<p>During one year I learned more than informatics, I also learned how a company runs, what its duties and responsibilities are, how I should behave in a professional environment, and how to find a balance between studies and job. It gave me fuel to take the next steps: quitting my first job, finding an internship, and winning a scholarship at one of the best private high schools in my hometown.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<p><small><sup>1</sup> AVRO is an Brazilian-based translation company.</small><br>
<small><em>To know more about AVROdx click on this link: <a href="https://www.avro.com.br/#avrodx">www.avro.com.br/#avrodx</a></em></small><br/>
<small><em>And click <a href="http://editor.avrodx.com.br/about/credits">here</a> to check the credits attributed to me as a contributing editor</em></small></p>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>