<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Micaelle Nogueira de Carvalho</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Micaelle Nogueira de Carvalho</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 15:21:48 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://micanogueira.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Professional</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/accomplishments/professional/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 15:21:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/accomplishments/professional/</guid><description>🔗 12/2017 ➛ 01/2014 Head of Finance at Sympla Created 4 departments from scratch – finance, administrative, human resources and personnel –, leading and operating them together for over a year. Led a team of 6 people, all hired to assume positions that I created. Implemented a new management concept, dividing finances into corporate and operational. It guaranteed accurate cash management and brought measurability to revenues, which had not been demonstrated before.</description></item><item><title>Educational</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/accomplishments/educational/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 15:21:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/accomplishments/educational/</guid><description>12/2017 ➛ 01/2014 Head of Finance at Sympla Created 4 departments from scratch – finance, administrative, human resources and personnel –, leading and operating them together for over a year. Led a team of 6 people, all hired to assume positions that I created. Implemented a new management concept, dividing finances into corporate and operational. It guaranteed accurate cash management and brought measurability to revenues, which had not been demonstrated before.</description></item><item><title>Started to study a Programming Language</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/learning_python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/learning_python/</guid><description>A latent aptitude When I was between 13 and14 years old, I really wanted to study computer science. Throughout my career, I have worked several times alongside the IT team, and the most I did was to design mock-ups of tools and features. I can say that I have always been close enough to learn to code. In fact, I always wanted to know how to code to be independent, to build my own tools and features, to meet my needs more quickly and autonomously.</description></item><item><title>Volunteered for a 36-hour hackathon</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/volunteer_hackillinois/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/volunteer_hackillinois/</guid><description>HackIllinois Every year, since 2014, on the last weekend of February, there is a 36-hour university hackathon run by students, the HackIllinois1. It brings in approximately 1,000 students from across the United States. An event like this requires a lot of teamwork. In the 2020 edition, I joined the team of volunteers, willing to help out the staff at any level.
The opportunity This opportunity came across because my husband is one of the mentors.</description></item><item><title>Started a German course</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_german/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_german/</guid><description>New year, new projects I love that feeling of starting something new at the beginning of the year. I was very excited to start learning German at a language school1 at last. On January 7th, I was completely lost on my first day of school. That first week was challenging. In the next two months, I realized that I was already quite acquainted with the language and enjoying learning it.</description></item><item><title>Travelled abroad to study English</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_london/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_london/</guid><description>English in Brazil In Latin America, Brazilians are the only ones who speak Portuguese. Even though we are surrounded by countries that have Spanish as its mother tongue, we do not have a second official language. It may be the reason that there&amp;rsquo;s no incentive to learn another language. In the second part of elementary education in public schools, English is mandatory, but it does not go beyond the basics. Taking an English course privately is something that does not fit the budget of most Brazilians.</description></item><item><title>Started to mentor startups and small businesses</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/mentoring_online/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/mentoring_online/</guid><description>The passion for mentoring awakens In mid-2019, I was approached by a person who lives in Brazil, asking for guidance in the development of his startup, which was at a very early stage. As I was about to travel to Brazil on vacation in a few weeks, I arranged to meet him in person and learn more about his project. We had some meetings during my stay in Brazil, and I started to mentor him and his partner.</description></item><item><title>Moved to another continent</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/moved_munich/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/moved_munich/</guid><description>Going abroad was always a dream: living a completely different lifestyle, exploring new experiences, getting used to other cultures and customs, learning a foreign language&amp;hellip; In mid-2016, I decided to include it on my wish list and add a purpose: studying abroad, which since my graduation had been a dream. I set as a goal a master&amp;rsquo;s degree related to economics and consumer behaviour. I also designated a starting point, starting in 2018, after my wedding.</description></item><item><title>Found out passion for mentoring</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/passion_mentoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/passion_mentoring/</guid><description>Promoting innovation and entrepreneurship A friend of mine who was also a former co-worker invited me to mentor in the &amp;ldquo;financial week&amp;rdquo; of a startup acceleration program1. I was very excited to have this opportunity to share knowledge and support the local startup ecosystem. As it couldn&amp;rsquo;t be different, my engagement went beyond that week. I became part of the examining board, judging the various early-stage startups, their business and their financial projections.</description></item><item><title>Got an MBA in Finance</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/postgraduate_mba/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/postgraduate_mba/</guid><description>The opportune time I had been pursuing an MBA since I was about to finish college. However, it only became possible three years later, which I can say was even better due to the professional and personal maturity that I have acquired so far.
Even amid a swirl of things to manage in my current job, getting an MBA in Finance represented an appropriate personal decision. The skills that I learned and improved perfectly fit the needs I had to fulfil in the scenario in which the company I worked for was, especially during its M&amp;amp;A (mergers and acquisitions) processes, which was something that I was leading and doing for the very first time.</description></item></channel></rss>