<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Micaelle Nogueira</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Micaelle Nogueira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://micanogueira.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Admitted to the Technical University of Munich</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/second_degree_tum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/second_degree_tum/</guid><description>A dream comes true Studying abroad has been a dream for over a decade! When I finally had the opportunity to live overseas, I set that as my main goal. While still in Brazil, I found TUM1, the Technical University of Munich, as the place where I wanted to study and build my academic life abroad. Getting admitted after an extensive application process was literally a dream come true!
By the way, this website is an outcome of my application for enrollment in the Bachelor in Management &amp;amp; Technology2 program, as a portfolio and a creative way to show an extension of my technical skills related to Computer Engineering, the field of specialization in technology that I chose in this program.</description></item><item><title>Documents</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/documents/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 16:41:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/documents/</guid><description>Click here to access my Curriculum Vitae
Click here to access my professional Resume</description></item><item><title>EC London Certificate</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/ec-london-certificate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 16:41:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/ec-london-certificate/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IELTS Certificate</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/ielts-certificate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 16:41:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/ielts-certificate/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Started taking private German lessons</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_german2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/studying_german2/</guid><description>New year, new beginnings I love that feeling of starting something new at the beginning of the year, even if it means restarting something!
In January 2020, I started a German course at a language school1 and completed the A1 module in about 2 months of intensive classes. However, it had to be stopped due to COVID-19 restrictions. In mid-May, I resumed the learning process using an online platform from an excellent German school2.</description></item><item><title>Professional</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/highlights/professional/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 15:21:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/highlights/professional/</guid><description>At a glance: achievements and highlights throughout my professional journey Head of Finance at Sympla - 4 yrs Had an incredible opportunity to build a startup from the ground up Joined the co-founders in their promising venture and supported them in building a company 50 times bigger than when we started, with 5 more offices in 5 different cities and nationally recognized as the market leader. Created 4 departments from scratch – finance, administrative, human resources and personnel –, leading and operating them together for over a year.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 15:21:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Micaelle 👋🏻 a Brazilian financial accounting specialist living in beautiful Munich, Germany. I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about leading people and driving business to understand their operations and results. After 12 uninterrupted years of building my career in Brazil, a new era began in my life when I moved to Munich. I&amp;rsquo;ve been filling this gap by honing other skills and focusing on integrating into the German way of life and also preparing to grasp opportunities here, on the other side of the Earth.</description></item><item><title>Educational</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/highlights/educational/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 15:21:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/highlights/educational/</guid><description>At a glance: achievements and highlights throughout my educational journey : ### Bachelor in Management &amp;amp; Technology at TUM
&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;eduperiod&amp;quot;&amp;gt;2021 ➛ Present&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;amp;nbsp;[Admitted to the Technical University of Munich] to be enrolled in the Bachelor of Science program in Management &amp;amp; Technology with a specialization in Computer Engineering. &amp;amp;nbsp;Pursuing a [second] undergraduate degree. MBA in Finance at IBMEC 2014 ➛ 2016 Accepted to enrol in the program as the youngest student in the class due to professional background equivalent to that of others with longer experience.</description></item><item><title>Learned my first Programming Language</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/learning_python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/learning_python/</guid><description>The unsuccessful attempt In mid-2015, I was very committed to learning a certain programming language, R1, due to my interest in furthering the studies in the statistics that I was studying on my MBA in finance. I decided to study alone, on weekends, the only free time I had. I had started an online course, but soon I realized that I should know the basics of programming first. I was stuck at the beginning of this course and gave up.</description></item><item><title>Volunteered for a 36-hour hackathon</title><link>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/volunteer_hackillinois/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://micanogueira.github.io/timeline/volunteer_hackillinois/</guid><description>HackIllinois Every year, since 2014, on the last weekend of February, there is a 36-hour university hackathon run by students, the HackIllinois1. It is the largest open-source hackathon in the world and brings in approximately 1,000 students from across the United States. An event like this requires a lot of teamwork. In the 2020 edition, I joined the team of volunteers, willing to help out the staff at any level.</description></item></channel></rss>